Konstantin Tenman

Software Engineer London, United Kingdom +44 7487 553781 konstantin@tenman.ee https://github.com/ktenman https://www.linkedin.com/in/ktenman

Profile

Self-motivated Software Developer with six years of experience including over five years of experience in Java development. My goal is to make software that is perfect for users and make an elegant programming code. I enjoy doing deep investigations, learning new technologies and always looking for ways to do things better. I would like to participate in true teamwork and develop new, useful and high standard IT systems.

Programming Skills

• Languages: Java 8+, TypeScript Technologies: Spring Boot, Angular 2+, Hibernate, Junit, Mockito

• Tools: Docker, PostgreSQL, AWS, Redis, Git, Jenkins, Maven, macOS, IntelliJ, SNS/SQS

EXPERIENCE

• Monese

Software Engineer

London, United Kingdom

Oct 2017 - Present

- Reduced costs by systematically working to improve software performance and decrease their operation costs. For one application, it's monthly operating cost was decreased for 50%.
- Increased revenue by doggedly identifying and fixing production issues. In one case, pursiong a fix for a single customer led to identifying a significant gap in profit.
- **Pricing**: Researched regarding breaking monolithic responsibility micro-services. Refactored and developed the pricing structure of the system. Delivered business priorities by completing new annual pricing fuctionality on-time and without any significant issues.
- Joint Accounts: Designed and developed the main logic around the Joint Accounts feature.
- Smart Transactions: Improved scalability of micro-services by separating read and write operation of database.
 Migrated gradually 120M payments to new queue based Java micro-service. Decreased average response time from 60ms to 5ms. Researched and introduced the new Angular 5 framework for internal tooling. Helped to improve seamless deployment in Amazon AWS.
- Recurring Payments: Introduced Spring Boot 2 with Java 10 with Junit 5, Mockito, AssertJ, integration tests. Created a micro-service with test coverage of up to 80%.
- Tools: Java 8-11, Angular, TypeScript, Grails, Scala, Docker, Amazon AWS, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, Google API, Mockito, Junit, Redis, AWS, CloudWatch, New Relic, Jenkins, Git, Intellij, Groovy, Testcontainers, Maven, Liquibase, Bootstrap, macOS

• Codeborne

Tallinn, Estonia

Full Stack Java Developer

Apr 2017 - Oct 2017

- Bank Saint-Petersburg: Developed internet banking website which is used by 2M customers and mobile application.
- Czech Expobank: Developed a responsive internet banking website for desktop and mobile platforms.
- o Tools: Java 8, RiotJS, Selenium, Mockito, TDD, Intellij, Agile, extreme programming, Play! Framework, Ubuntu

Full Stack Java Developer

Tallinn, Estonia

Jun 2016 - Apr 2017

- Developed a full-stack web-based application where users create services and search for them through Google Maps.
- **Technologies**: AngularJS, Java 8, Docker, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JHipster, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Protractor, Maven, Liquibase, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, Ubuntu, Git

EDUCATION

• Knowit

• Tallinn University

Estonia